export const GEOGRAPHYA2020 = [

{
id: "question1",
question:  "1. The scale of the map is",
A: "1 cm to ½ km.",
B: "1 cm to 1 km.",
C: "1 cm to 2 km.",
D: "2 cm to 3 km.",
answer: "B. 1 cm to 1 km.",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question2",
question:  "2. The height of Point P is about",
A: "275m.",
B: "300m.",
C: "375m.",
D: "350m.",
answer: "D. 350m.",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question3",
question:  "3. The contour interval on the map is",
A: "50m.",
B: "200m",
C: "250m.",
D: "300m.",
answer: "A. 50m.",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question4",
question:  "4. What is the approximate distance from Obasa to Oju as the crow flies?",
A: "10km",
B: "18km",
C: "20km",
D: "25km",
answer: "A. 10km",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question5",
question:  "5. The bearing of Danki from Oju is",
A: "90°.",
B: "150o.",
C: "285o.",
D: "355o.",
answer: "C. 285O.",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question6",
question:  "6. The feature in the South-West of Musa is",
A: "a cliff.",
B: "an island.",
C: "a cave.",
D: "an inselberg.",
answer: "A. a cliff.",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question7",
question:  "7. The lower section of R. Kam is showing signs of old stage because of the presence of",
A: "spur.",
B: "levee.",
C: "pothole.",
D: "meander.",
answer: "C. pothole.",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question8",
question:  "8. Musa settlement is likely to be",
A: "an airport.",
B: "a fishing village.",
C: "a confluence town.",
D: "a nodal town.",
answer: "B. a fishing village.",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question9",
question:  "9. A seaport can be sited in all the following settlements except",
A: "Kalu.",
B: "Musa.",
C: "Obasa.",
D: "Bama.",
answer: "D. Bama.",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question10",
question:  "10. All the following settlements are intervisible from KUSH except",
A: "Oju.",
B: "Danki.",
C: "Musa.",
D: "Kalu.",
answer: "D. Kalu.",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question11",
question:  "11. The annual range of temperature is",
A: "1°C.",
B: "2°C",
C: "22°C",
D: "28°C",
answer: "B. 2°C",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question12",
question:  "12. Which climatic region is represented by the data?",
A: "Desert",
B: "Mediterranean",
C: "Equatorial",
D: "Tropical Monsoon",
answer: "C. Equatorial",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question13",
question:  "13. Which of the following towns experiences the type of climate presented?",
A: "Gao (Mali)",
B: "Cairo (Egypt)",
C: "Warri (Nigeria)",
D: "London (England)",
answer: "C. Warri (Nigeria)",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question14",
question:  "14. The mean temperature from July to December is",
A: "16.5 °C.",
B: "17.2°C.",
C: "27.5°C",
D: "28.2 °C.",
answer: "C. 27.5°C",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question15",
question:  "15. The type C of Koppen’s climate is the",
A: "warm temperate.",
B: "tropical continental.",
C: "humid continental.",
D: "hot desert.",
answer: "C. humid continental.",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question16",
question:  "16. A fall in sea level can lead to the formation of",
A: "mud flat.",
B: "raised beach.",
C: "tombolo.",
D: "glup.",
answer: "A. mud flat.",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question17",
question:  "17. Which of the following is a process of river transportation?",
A: "Attrition",
B: "Deflation",
C: "Abrasion",
D: "Suspension",
answer: "A. Attrition",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question18",
question:  "18. Which of the following are processes of physical weathering?  I. Frost action  II. Hydrolysis  III. Oxidation  IV. Temperature changes",
A: "I and III only",
B: "I and IV only",
C: "III and IV only",
D: "II and III only",
answer: "B. I and IV only",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question19",
question:  "19. Town A is located on longitude 15 °E while town B is located on longitude 45 °E. If the local time in town  A is 6.00 am, what will be the local time in town B?",
A: "4.00 pm",
B: "4.00",
C: "8.00 pm",
D: "8.00 am",
answer: "D. 8.00 am",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question20",
question:  "20. The predominant process of weathering in desert regions is",
A: "biological.",
B: "chemical.",
C: "erosional.",
D: "physical.",
answer: "D. physical.",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question21",
question:  "21. Which of the following factors affect temperature?  I. Latitude  II. Time  III. Wind direction  IV. Ocean current",
A: "I and II only",
B: "II and III only",
C: "II and IV only",
D: "I and IV only",
answer: "D. I and IV only",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question22",
question:  "22. Which climate is characterized by winter rain and summer drought?",
A: "Equatorial",
B: "Mediterranean",
C: "Tropical continental",
D: "Tropical hinterland",
answer: "B. Mediterranean",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question23",
question:  "23. Temperature decreases with height in the",
A: "stratosphere.",
B: "troposphere.",
C: "ionosphere.",
D: "exosphere.",
answer: "B. troposphere.",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question24",
question:  "24. The temporary Salt Lake found in arid and semi-arid areas is also called",
A: "playa.",
B: "wadi.",
C: "bajada.",
D: "mesa.",
answer: "A. playa.",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question25",
question:  "25. Hamada is another name for",
A: "sandy desert.",
B: "stony desert.",
C: "rocky desert.",
D: "cold desert.",
answer: "C. rocky desert.",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question26",
question:  "26. Petroleum is usually found in",
A: "resistant rocks.",
B: "metamorphic rocks.",
C: "igneous rocks.",
D: "sedimentary rocks.",
answer: "D. sedimentary rocks.",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question27",
question:  "27. One of the following features is an example of faulting",
A: "Plateau",
B: "Caldera",
C: "Rift valley",
D: "Fold mountain",
answer: "C. Rift valley",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question28",
question:  "28. How many Standard Time Zones will a country with a longitudinal extent of 165° have?",
A: "9",
B: "11",
C: "15",
D: "16",
answer: "B. 11",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question29",
question:  "29. The day in which the length of day and night are equal everywhere on Earth is",
A: "31st June.",
B: "30th August.",
C: "21st March.",
D: "22nd December.",
answer: "C. 21st March.",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question30",
question:  "30. A rock in which water cannot easily pass through is termed",
A: "permeable.",
B: "porous.",
C: "impermeable.",
D: "aquifer.",
answer: "C. impermeable.",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question31",
question:  "31. A great circle route is used to",
A: "avoid long flights over deserts.",
B: "save time and fuel.",
C: "avoid flying near the North Pole.",
D: "avoid flying over long distance barriers",
answer: "A. avoid long flights over deserts.",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question32",
question:  "32. The difference between the hottest and coldest months of a place is the",
A: "length of the hot season.",
B: "mean annual temperature.",
C: "annual range of temperature.",
D: "total monthly temperature.",
answer: "C. annual range of temperature.",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question33",
question:  "33. Which of the following is not a proof of the spherical shape of the Earth?",
A: "Ship’s visibility",
B: "Circular horizon",
C: "Lunar eclipse",
D: "Coastal submergence",
answer: "D. Coastal submergence",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question34",
question:  "34. A plateau highly eroded by rivers and broken by deep narrow valleys is",
A: "intermont plateau.",
B: "volcanic plateau.",
C: "dissected plateau.",
D: "lava plateau.",
answer: "C. dissected plateau.",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question35",
question:  "35. Calculate the distance between town Y which is on latitude 40°N and town Z which is on latitude 10o S.",
A: "1110km",
B: "3330km",
C: "4440km",
D: "5550 km",
answer: "D. 5550 km",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question36",
question:  "36. Which of the following problems hinder international trade?  I. Political instability  II. Low tariffs III. Inadequate foreign exchange  IV. Strained relations",
A: "I, II and IV only",
B: "II, III and IV only",
C: "I, II and III only",
D: "I, III and IV only",
answer: "D. I, III and IV only",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question37",
question:  "37. The hinterland of a port is",
A: "deepest part of the port.",
B: "container section of a port.",
C: "walled area of a port.",
D: "area served by a port.",
answer: "D. area served by a port.",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question38",
question:  "38. Which of the following are benefits of transportation to a country?  I. Diffusion of ideas  II. Acculturation  III. Unemployment  IV. Enhanced trade",
A: "II, II and IV only",
B: "I, II and IV only",
C: "I, II and III only",
D: "I, III and IV only",
answer: "B. I, II and IV only",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question39",
question:  "39. Which of the following are characteristics of manufacturing industries in Tropical Africa?  I. Export-oriented  II. Labour intensive  III. Consumer-oriented  IV. Diversified production",
A: "I and II only",
B: "II and III only",
C: "I and IV only",
D: "I and III only",
answer: "B. II and III only",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question40",
question:  "40. Which factor for location of industries explains the establishment of cement industries near areas of limestone deposits?",
A: "Market orientation",
B: "Income source",
C: "Source of raw material",
D: "Availability of capital",
answer: "C. Source of raw material",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question41",
question:  "41. The major problem facing the railway transportation compared to road transportation is",
A: "low patronage.",
B: "excessive speed.",
C: "inadequate manpower.",
D: "lack of flexibility.",
answer: "D. lack of flexibility.",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question42",
question:  "42. Which of the following is not a Sea route?",
A: "London → Moscow → Baghdad",
B: "London → Cape Town → Melbourne",
C: "New York → London → Rotterdam",
D: "Sydney → Suez → London",
answer: "A. London → Moscow → Baghdad",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question43",
question:  "43. One characteristic feature of intensive farming is that, it is practised in urban centres where",
A: "water supply is inadequate.",
B: "human population is high.",
C: "human population is low.",
D: "demand for produce is low.",
answer: "B. human population is high.",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question44",
question:  "44. Which of the following features promote the development of nucleated settlement?",
A: "Narrow valleys and rugged highlands",
B: "Dissected plains and nodal centres",
C: "Nodal centres and natural harbours",
D: "Fertile soils and steep valleys",
answer: "C. Nodal centres and natural harbours",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question45",
question:  "45. In an economy where the major problem to industrial development is the fear of failure, the most important policy to revitalize the industrial sector of such an economy is",
A: "large capital in form of loan.",
B: "large pool of labor.",
C: "development of innovative entrepreneurs.",
D: "creation of industrial estates.",
answer: "C. development of innovative entrepreneurs.",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question46",
question:  "46. Which of the following economic activities makes use of land and sea breezes?",
A: "Lumbering",
B: "Hunting",
C: "Fishing",
D: "Mining",
answer: "A. Lumbering",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question47",
question:  "47. An example of local craft industry is",
A: "pottery.",
B: "ship building.",
C: "fish preservation.",
D: "sand winning.",
answer: "A. pottery.",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question48",
question:  "48. A dominant factor that explains the establishment of industries in some rural areas of Tropical Africa is",
A: "development of rural areas.",
B: "encouragement of rural-urban migration.",
C: "reduction of crime in rural areas.",
D: "traffic congestion in rural areas.",
answer: "A. development of rural areas.",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question49",
question:  "49. The main difference between town and village is that",
A: "village has more food storage facility.",
B: "village has more occupations.",
C: "town performs more tertiary function.",
D: "town has more unqualified workers.",
answer: "C. town performs more tertiary function.",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question50",
question:  "50. The mode of transportation which is best used to convey perishable goods is",
A: "air.",
B: "rail.",
C: "road.",
D: "pipeline",
answer: "A. air.",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},


]